TalentLens — Explainable AI Ranking Engine
Built for the Redrob Hackathon 2026
by Ruthvik Goud
Ranks 100,000 candidates for a
Senior AI Engineer role
Four-Stage Ranking Pipeline —
fully local, no API calls
35% Career Evidence & Trajectory
25% Recruitability Index
25% Explicit Skill Relevance
15% Semantic TF-IDF Match
Weighted Score Formula:
final_score = max(0, weighted - honeypot × 0.10)
100,000 candidates ingested
↓
1,000 semantic matches filtered
100 ranked by multi-signal scoring
↓
10 finalists selected
🥇 Gold: CAND_0086022 — Score 77.24
Senior Applied Scientist
🥈 Silver: CAND_0079387 — Score 76.79
🥉 Bronze: CAND_0005649 — Score 76.56
Top 100 ranked candidates
with full explainable reasoning
Every score is traceable.
Every decision is explainable.
TalentLens · ruthvikgoud16 · GitHub
Redrob Hackathon 2026